Nicholas Michalak

Quantitative Social Scientist

Ann Arbor, MI402-917-3423

□ nickmm@umich.edu

in linkedin.com/in/nmmichalak/

nickmichalak.com

Summary

A quantitative social scientist with 9 years of experience using advanced methods and statistics to answer a breadth of research questions in marketing, consumer behavior, social psychology, and survey methodology. Proficient in R, Python, SQL, and SPSS.

Work Experience

Methods and Statistics Consultant

2017 - Present

University of Michigan, Department of Psychology

Consulted dozens of research faculty, post-doctoral researcher, doctoral student, master's student, and undergraduate student clients on methodological and statistical rigor of and data visualization for their experimental, quasi-experimental, and observational studies

Graduate Student Instructor

2015 - 2019

University of Michigan, Department of Psychology

Trained hundreds of doctoral and master's students in advanced statistical methods, computing, and data visualization

Instructed statistical topics including Generalized Linear Model, ANOVA, Multidimensional Scaling, Clustering, Principal Components and Common Factor Analysis, Reliability, Structural Equation Modeling, Power Analysis, and Missing Data

Research Lab Manager

2013 - 2015

Carlson School of Management, Marketing and Logistics

Conducted 75 experiments and observational studies in psychology, marketing, and consumer behavior

Regularly prepared quantitative social science research reports as well as PowerPoint presentations for invited speaking

Education

Doctor of Philosophy

2015 - 2020

University of Michigan

Social Psychology

Master of Science

2015 - 2017

University of Michigan

Social Psychology

Bachelor of Science

2007 - 2012

University of St. Thomas (St. Paul, MN)

Neuroscience